Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to Reel Tapes, 1961-1984
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Reel to reel tapes added from other University at Buffalo sources with Mikhashoff as performer or composer, circa 1970-1981, V.; Item 185-216
  - Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Reel to reel tapes, Tape 216, 1981-06-28, 1 10.5 inch reel; Container title: Nightclub operas - Mikhashoff 6/28/81 Performers: Mikhashoff, piano; Thomas Halpin, violin; Kyle Peterson, clarinet Recording location: University at Buffalo, Baird Recital Hall Printed pro
Ganz, Isabelle (soprano) 8, 46, 57, 64, 65, 66; see also: Isabelle Lipschutz
Gorusso, Anthony (trumpet) 64, 65, 66
Grant, [?] (voice) 5
Halpin, Thomas (violin) 53, 54, 55, 56, 58, 59, 60, 97, 98, 99, 101, 102, 104, 105, 108
Hatt, Gary (clarinet) 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, 69
Havens, Neil (narrator) 7
Hemke, Frederick L. (conductor) 45
Herbert, David (oboe) 4, 15, 17, 24, 25, 27, 31
Herdliska, Phyllis (viola) 13, 14, 15, 17
Hill, Connie (soprano) 12
Hirsh, Albert (piano) 4
Hohensee, Kevin (bassoon) 64, 65, 66
Huber, Susan (basson) 64, 65, 66
Hudson, Ben (violin) 37, 38
Hunter, Amy (flute) 4; see also: Amy Winn
Jacobsen, Svatara 28, 29, 30
Jelinek, Josef (flute) 178
Jeter, James (bassoon) 25, 27
Jones, Mark (tuba) 64, 65, 66
Jungerman, Mary (clarinet) 12, 15, 17, 25, 26, 27, 31
Justen, Wolfgang (guitar) 13, 14, 57
Kasprowicz, James (conductor) 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, 69, 100
Kasprowicz, James (trombone) 71, 72
Katz, Mathew (horn) 64, 65, 66
Kennedy, Patricia (percussion) 7
Kenneson, Carolyn (viola) 173
Kirkpatrick, William (dancer-choreographer) 70
Kirkwood, James (cello) 107
Kirkwood, Linda Walton (viola) 107
Knittel, Weronika (violin) 74
Kogan, Robert (cello) 1
Kubera, Joseph (piano) 53, 54, 55, 56
Lee, Mary Elisabety (harpsichord) 7
Lerner, Jeffrey (conductor) 10
Lina, Kathy (horn) 64, 65, 66
Lipschutz, Isabelle (soprano) 7, 12-15, 17, 24, 25, 27-30, 42, 43; see also: Isabelle Ganz
Loriod, Yvonne (pianist) 152
Lowe, Joanne (viola) 64, 65, 66
Lutzky, Susan (piccolo) 64, 65, 66
MacKay, Ronald (piano) 1, 3, 4, 6, 9
Manes, Stephen (piano) 37
Mare, Anthony de (piano) 102
Maris, Barbara (piano) 148
Martin, Dave (baritone) 1
Marvin, Stephen (viola) 53, 54, 55, 56
Maynard, William (clarinet) 1
McCathern, Jerry (trumpet) 7, 10
McNabb, Michael (electronics) 138
Mehta, Phiroze (piano) 154, 155
Metzmacher, Ingo (conductor) 187
Mikhashoff, Yvar (conductor) 7
Mikhashoff, Yvar (piano) 2, 5, 8, 10, 11, 16, 18-22, 26, 32-36, 38, 40, 41-44, 47-56, 58-90, 93-115, 117-123, 130, 174-179, 181-183
Mikhashoff, (piano, director) 12-15, 17, 24, 25, 27-30, 31, 57
Mings, David (bassoon) 15, 17
Moran, Robert (stage direction) 51, 52
Moran, Robert (piano) 177
Nunemaker, Richard (clarinets) 57
Orsted, Ole (electronics) 179
Oliver, Lester (tenor tuba) 10
Palma, Donald (bass) 149
Panfil, Mark (banjo) 64, 65, 66
Park, Sandra (bass clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Parten, Billy (trumpet) 10
Pearce, Farley (cello) 64, 65, 66
Pecora, Peter (clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Peress, Maurice (conductor) 34
Pinto, Carlo (conductor) 64, 65, 66
Plantamura, Carol (soprano) 67, 68, 69
Post, Nora (oboe) 67, 68, 69
Pugliese, Michael (vibraphone) 74
Rapport, Toni (violin) 1
Rehfuss, Heinz (bass-baritone) 51, 52, 64, 65, 66
Richards, Ronald (oboe) 88, 89
Rothenberg, Allen (contrabass clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Rusinak, Dana (cello) 37
Russel, Andy (trombone) 10
Rzewski, Frederic 169
Salvatore, Ramon (piano) 154, 155
Scelsi, Giacinto (piano) 169
Schafer, R. Murray 157
Schlossman, Paul (oboe) 39
Schmidt, Paul (speaker-narrator) 13, 14, 20, 21, 22, 47, 57
Schoettle, Mary (piano) 57
Shannon, Robert (piano) 144
Shook, Barbara (violin) 7
Sigel, Allen (clarinet) 53, 54, 55, 56, 104, 105
Silversteen, Rosemary (violin) 13, 14
[Sime?] (conductor) 145
Simmons, Paul (alto saxophone) 64, 65, 66
Simpson, Winifred (soprano) 51, 52
Skiff, Trudy Kier (soprano) 35
Smart, Gary (piano) 146
Smit, Leo (piano) 97, 98, 99, 100, 101
Smit, Leo (piano, speaker) 51, 52
Smith, Walker (saxophone) 15, 17, 45
Spain, Patti (mezzo-soprano) 57
Spotts, Carleton (cello) 173
Standaart, Peter (flute) 151
Stern, Holly (violin) 173
Strauss, Richard 143
Summerville, [Suzanne?] (voice) 5
Szekey, Era (violin) 173
Thiel, Samuel (french horn) 13, 14
Thornhill, Charles (narrator) 33
Tobola, Diane (soprano) 24, 25, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 57
Tremont String Quartet 107
Tusa, Erzsebet 168
Uitti, Frances-Marie (cello) 58-60, 67-69, 73, 75, 81, 82, 93-95
Ungaro, Deborah (clarinet) 64, 65, 66, 88, 89
University of Massachusetts Group for New Music 173
University of Illinois Opera Group 145
University Philharmonia of SUNY Buffalo 100
University Symphony Orchestra and University Symphonic Wind Ensemble 45
Vandiver, David (trombone) 10
Virginia, Mary (clarinet) 64, 65, 66
Waldron, Craig (tenor saxophone) 64, 65, 66
Watson, Linda (pianist) 12
Weimer, Martin (trumpet) 64, 65, 66
Weiss, Debbie (violin) 64, 65, 66
Wells, Richard (saxophone) 151
White, Mike (flute) 10
Willey, James (piano) 107, 153, 156
Williams, Jan (conductor) 67, 68, 69
Williams, Jan (percussion) 74, 108
Wilson, Marian (violoncello, viola da gamba) 7
Winn, Amy (flute) 2, 12, 15-17, 20, 24, 25, 27, 31, 42, 43, 57; see also Amy Hunter
Wullen, Lynn (violin) 53-56
Yamazaki, Keiko (violin) 53-56
Zeagler, Wesley (trombone) 10
Zeavin, Carol (violin) 37
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Collections
The Yvar Mikhashoff Collections contain the following separate components. Descriptions can be found at LibGuide page for the Yvar Mikhashoff archival resources at
https://research.lib.buffalo.edu/mikhashoff/archival
:
Yvar Mikhashoff Collections of Compositions, Transcriptions, Annotated Scores, Tangos, Reel to reel Recordings, Video Recordings, and Photographs
North American New Music Festival papers and recordings